💌 abokahfa@gmail.com | 🛅 som3aware | 🕥 ahmedsomaa | 🥒 +20 100-940-8401

### **Profile**

Skilled Full Stack Software Engineer with 4+ years of hands-on experience in Single Page Applications, RESTful & APIs with a willingness to master Front-end Development Software Engineering Management & to become a Design Engineer. React specialist.

Experience

## Senior FrontEnd Software Engineer

Jan 2023 - Present

Herwin Software

Dover, Delware (Freelance Remote)

- Developing new product features for the front-end interface of an invoice reconciliation process application using Nextis.
- · Improving the aesthetic appeal and user experience (UX) of the front-end interface for smoother invoice reconciliation processes.
- Integrating with third-party services and internal APIs to streamline data exchange and enhance functionality within the system.
- · Integrating with third-party analytics tools through Twilio Segment to track page views and events to get insights about the user's behavior.

### **Software Engineer II**

May - Dec. 2023

Nodogoro

*New Cairo*, *Egypt (Full-time Remote)* 

- Full Stack development of an ads' analyzer tool for the Konstant Kreative client to analyze an image ad, provide feedback and convert that feedback to creative briefs using Next.js, GPT-4 Vision API, Tailwindcss, and shadcn/ui components.
- Oversaw the maintenance and enhancement of the Konstant Kreative platform on Bubble, proactively addressing reported bugs and implementing new functionalities to ensure optimal performance.
- · Collaborated on the development of a Slackbot tool enabling user queries across diverse data sources (Google Drive, Calendar, Gmail, ClickUp, Fireflies...etc.). Ingested the data from google sources into the bot's vector database (Pinecone) using Node, Langchain, and Google APIs.
- Participated in the company hackathon, NodoAI, to develop a resume screening tool that allows recruiters to input job descriptions and qualifications and ask questions about candidate resumes using Python, LangChain, and OpenAI.
- · Collaborated on building a cost saving scraping scripts that try to dynamically fetch similar prices for a given product from various online retail stores using python, LangChain, OpenAI, and Selenium web driver.
- Led the development of Outlined AI, a transformative mobile app extracting transcripts from audio/video files and providing users with features such as summaries, notes, and common questions using WhisperAPI, OpenAI, React Native, Node.js, and FFmpeg.

## Software Engineer I

Nov 2021 - May 2023

New Smart Egypt for Integrated Solutions

*Nasr City, Egypt (Full-time Hybrid)* 

- Full Stack development of an ad server like dashboard for the Ramsis Station's Free Wi-Fi website to handle multiple advertisers' requests to display their ads on the website.
- Development of a client application for the face-api.js library to detect user's face expressions, age and gender, and extended it to become a Face Attendance app.
- · Configuration and integration of ZKTeco MA500 Fingerprint scanner & ZKTeco MB2000 with Microsoft SQL Server and .NET core APIs to be integrated with Odoo ERP attendance module.
- Full Stack development of the Android ECARD mobile application for the Egyptian Company for Agricultural and Rural Development using the Expo framework, .NET Core Web API & Microsoft SQL Server.
- Refactoring the legacy code base for the Ramsis Station's Free Wi-Fi website & improving its performance on mobile phones.
- Full deployment of the ECARD RESTful API services and the SQL Server database on the Etisalat cloud using Internet Information Services (IIS) and .NET Core hosting bundle on Microsoft Windows Server 2019.

# **Software Engineer**

Jul 2020 - Oct 2021

VOIS

Smart Village, Egypt (Full-time Hybrid)

· Design and implementation of new UI components & pages for a call center system to measure the performance metrics of a call center agent using React, Redux Toolkit, & Uber's React-Vis.

- Profiling, Troubleshooting & Bugs fixes for a full stack COVID-19 tracker web application built with React, Redux, Node.js & Mapbox GL JS.
- Developing new and customization of the existing features for a web portal for employees to access & enjoy their benefits using Angular & .NET Core.
- Revamping UI, UX and overall design aesthetic of a React Component Library following the company's design system using React & AWS Lambda functions with Node.js.
- Refined and improved the existing code for the RESTful API Services of the COVID-19 tracker and the react component library projects using Node.js & Express.

#### Education

## **Arizona State University**

Online

Masters of Science in Engineering in Software Engineering

Jan 2022 - Dec 2023

• AGFE OLSP Scholarship, 4.0/4.0

Udacity

Online

React Development Cross-Skilling Nanodegree Program

Dec 2022

• Covered React, React Lifecycle, React Hooks, React Router & Redux.

**Udacity** 

Online

Advanced Full-Stack Web Development Nanodegree Program

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022

 Covered TypeScript, Node.js, Express, Jasmine, PostgreSQL, JWT, Elasticbeanstalk, AWS S3, CircleCI, bash scripting & create documentation using markdown files and diagrams.

# The American University in Cairo

New Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Sep 2014 – Jul 2019

• Egyptian Public Schools Scholarship, 3.0/4.0

#### Core Skills

**Languages**: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C++, Java. **Front-end**: HTML5, CSS3, React, React Native, Next.js.

Back-end: Node.js, Express, Dotnet Core, OpenAI, LangChain, FastAPI.

.NET Development: ASP.NET Web API, SOAP, WCF, WF, SOA.

**SDLC**: Agile, Scrum, JIRA, Azure DevOps, Trello Boards.

**DevOps**: Travis CI, CircleCI, Git, GitHub, GitHub Actions, CI/CD. **Databases**: MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB. **Cloud**: Azure, AWS Lambda, AWS S3, Surge, Vercel, Netlify.

Developer Tools: VS Code, Visual Studio, DataGrip, SSMS, ASU VIPLE, AnyDesk.

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

## **Vodafone Ambassador**

Apr 2019

AUC Employment Fair

AUC, New Cairo, Egypt

- Represented Vodafone as an Ambassador at the Fair, actively engaging with participants and showcasing the company's opportunities and values.
- Facilitated networking between prospective candidates and Vodafone recruiters, contributing to a positive and impactful presence for the company at the Fair.

## **Participant**

Feb 2019

Dell EMC 423x Hackathon

Dell-EMC, New Cairo, Egypt

• Worked with my team on solving the Mars Challenge.

# **Participant**

Aug 2018

Hajj Hackathon

Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

• Developed with my team an innovative application named 'Kun 3awnan' ('Be Helpful'), that leverages the IoT devices in Masjid al-Haram to offer real-time assistance to pilgrims.